Good morning!
早安
Here are your medical check-up notices.
這是健康檢查的通知
Thank you.
謝謝
It's that time of year again.
又到了這時候啊
I was flagged during last year's breast cancer screening.
我在去年的乳癌篩檢被標記了
You were?
是喔？
They checked it again and it turned out to be nothing.
不過複檢後就沒事了
Let's hope there's no abnormalities this year.
希望今年也沒有異常就好了
Right.
是啊
My love life is abnormal enough.
我心中倒是滿滿的異常
He keeps his nose like…
他很常像這樣…
It was so fun being together.
在一起時明明很開心的
But because I made a move on him too quickly…
但也是因為我突然上前…
Kagiya?
鍵谷？
I'm sorry.
對不起
Wait, Kagiya!
等一下，鍵谷
Because I was too aggressive,
因為我太主動了
he must have been put him off.
所以他退縮了吧？
WHERE ARE YOU? WHAT'S GOING ON? CALL ME, PLEASE PICK UP, LET'S TALK
（你在哪裡？怎麼回事？ 打給我，拜託，我們在電話裡談談）
You know, to begin with,
說到底
the reason I work so hard is because I'm thinking about our future together.
我會這麼拼命工作 還不是為了我們的未來著想
If we were to get married, I'd have to work the hardest.
如果我們要結婚 我不多努力點怎麼行？
You only make half of what I do. If you don't even get--
你的年收入只有我的一半，你根本…
Makoto?
真？
I was being a bit too harsh, but still…
我說得是有點過分，但也不至於…
Miyuki.
美由紀
What?
幹嘛？
Here. It's the medical check-up notice.
這個，健康檢查通知
Thanks.
謝謝
You look pale. Are you okay?
你的臉色看起來不太好，還好嗎？
If that's all, just go. Even if you aren't, some of us are busy.
沒事的話就快走吧 我可不像你，很忙的
What?
什麼啦？
Why are you always so irritable?
為什麼你總是這麼緊繃？
I know we weren't on good terms when I quit before,
我知道我之前辭職的時候 我們關係不太好
but that was 13 years ago.
但也過了13年了
Are you that obsessed with me?
你也太執著了吧？
Excuse me?
什麼？
I don't actually care about you whatsoever.
你怎麼樣我才不管呢
I see.
這樣啊
Then don't make that face at me.
那就別露出那種表情嘛
You look scary.
很可怕的
What do you mean, scary?
什麼很可怕啊？
Like a monster.
就像怪物一樣
Try thinking about it with the genders reversed, please.
把性別反過來思考看看吧
If it had been a man inviting her home,
如果男生邀女生到家裡
and he suddenly took her hand and tried to kiss her.
然後突然間握住女方的手要接吻
Anyone would pull back. It's creepy.
誰都會退縮的吧，很噁心吧？
Guess I was creepy.
原來我很噁心啊
But if he wasn't interested at all,
但要是男方沒興趣的話
wouldn't he have declined the invitation to come over?
女生邀請的時候就會拒絕了吧？
That's true.
就是說啊
That doesn't mean he consented to it.
那也不代表他同意吧？
Some people don't want sexual intimacy.
有些人就是不想要親密行為
Could it be Kagiya is also asexual?
該不會鍵谷也是無性戀吧？
He doesn't look like it.
看起來不像啊
Though neither does Hara.
但阿原也看不出來
I can't figure this out.
我不知道啦
If you can't figure it out, you're simply going to have to ask them.
不知道的話，就只能去問本人了吧？
THE OTHER DAY
（前幾天）
I can't.
辦不到啊
Give me a break!
好煩喔
I forgot about that.
我忘記了
HEALTH CHECKUP QUESTIONNAIRE
（健康檢查問卷）
"Have you engaged in sexual activities?"
“是否有過性經驗？”
That one again…
又是這個問題…
Every year, I have to publicly document that I've never had sex.
每年都要在公家機關的 文件裡寫下沒有性經驗的事
The embarrassment, emptiness and misery it brings…
這份羞恥、空虛和艱辛…
HAVE YOU ENGAGED IN SEXUAL ACTIVITIES?
（是否有過性經驗？）
NO
（否）
If I had experience,
如果我有經驗的話
would things have gone better with Kagiya?
是不是就能跟鍵谷更順利呢？
MARRIED - UNMARRIED
（已婚、未婚）
I was too focused on making sure I could support myself.
我一直為了讓自己能獨立生活而拼命
My family is poor
老家並不有錢
so I was studying and working when everyone else was having fun.
周圍的人都在玩的時候 我一邊讀書一邊打工
Even after getting a full-time job
就算有正職之後
I made sure to learn the job so I could make money quickly.
我也為了要能盡快賺錢而拼命工作
I can always get married anytime.
我覺得我隨時都能結婚
Or so I thought.
至少我是這麼想的
If I knew I'd feel this way, it would have been easier to stay alone forever.
如果會這麼難過 一直單身還比較快樂
I'm sorry.
非常抱歉
It's not like you're new at this,
就因為你已經不是菜鳥了
so how could you not double-check before adding the photo?
怎麼能沒有確認照片就放上去呢？
I'm terribly sorry.
真的非常抱歉
Ms. Kosaka.
香坂小姐
You're making a lot of mistakes lately.
你最近出的包是不是有點多？
I've been spending all my time fixing your messes.
為了彌補你的錯誤 我的工作完全沒有進度
Well now, everyone makes mistakes.
好了，大家都會犯錯
Ms. Kosaka might have had a lot going on in her personal life.
說不定香坂的私生活也發生很多事嘛
That's not an excuse.
那不是藉口
Everyone has their issues, but we all work hard.
大家都有各自的問題 但也都努力地工作
If your personal life is that important, then just get married and quit already.
那麼注重私生活的話 不如早早結婚辭職算了
Some of us are too busy to just lounge around.
我可不是來打工的
Hurry up and fix it.
趕快修正
I'm sorry.
非常抱歉
It wasn't anything to get that mad about.
沒必要這麼生氣吧？
I'm becoming a monster again.
我又變成怪物了
Let's be careful.
小心點吧
Y-MARKET: STORE WIDE SALE EVENT
（Y超市：全店特賣）
WHERE ARE YOU? WHAT'S GOING ON?
（你在哪裡？怎麼回事？）
I'LL WAIT, TODAY IS YAKISOBA
（我等你，今天吃炒麵喔）
I never replied.
我還沒有回覆
I wonder when Makoto's kindness became something I took for granted.
不知道從什麼時候開始 就把真的溫柔當成理所當然
Even though I was only able to work so hard
我能這麼努力工作
because he was there for me.
是因為有他在支持著我
I don't know what to do. What if he never comes back?
怎麼辦？他是不是不會回來了？
That hurt.
好痛
Miyuki?
美由紀？
Are you okay?
你沒事吧？
Tsuji…
辻…
There you go.
好了
Thanks.
謝謝
I live close around here too.
我也住在這附近
What?
是喔？
I've seen you going home a few times, but I couldn't approach you.
我好幾次看到你回家 但都沒有和你搭話
You always looked so scary.
因為你總是一副可怕的表情
Why were you crying?
你為什麼在哭？
I-I wasn't crying.
我…我才沒有哭
Huh?
咦？
I'm certain you were crying.
我以為一定在哭呢
Right. You probably had a stomach ache.
哎呀，原來是肚子痛啊？
Of course that's not it.
怎麼可能？
My boyfriend left.
我男朋友離家出走了
Huh? What?
咦？什麼？
What? Wait a minute, you have a boyfriend?
等一下，你有男朋友喔？
Hurry up, tell me, what is he like?
快點，快告訴我是什麼樣的人？
Is he handsome? Or cute? Or like a teddy bear?
帥哥系、可愛系還是熊系男友？
You take me for a fool, don't you?
你覺得我是笨蛋吧？
What?
什麼？
All I do is work and then my boyfriend ditches me too.
只會拼命工作 結果連男朋友都逃跑了
You're married and got it all figured out, so you enjoy looking down on me.
因為你結婚過得順風順水 所以居高臨下地看我很有趣吧？
You only think so because you're the one taking me for a fool.
你會那樣想 是因為你把我當成笨蛋了吧？
What?
什麼意思？
The reason I got married and left was because I could never be like you.
我會結婚辭職 是因為我不可能和你一樣
I knew, no matter how hard I tried
我知道無論我多努力工作
I would never be important to them like you are.
也不可能和你一樣被大家需要
So I figured I'd make a family instead.
所以我才想要成家
But…
但是…
It's not easy to become important to someone.
想被人需要真是困難啊
I think my husband is cheating,
我老公好像外遇了
and my son is in his rebellious, hateful phase.
兒子正處於叛逆期，讓人受不了
No matter how elaborate the food I cook is, no one ever says anything.
不管多麼用心做菜 也沒有人會稱讚一句
I'm so tired of it.
我受夠了
I don't know why I can tell you all of this.
為什麼在你面前就能一吐為快呢？
I couldn't even tell my friends or family.
我從來沒跟主婦朋友和家人說過
You know,
我啊
the period we spent as friends was the most fun I've ever had.
跟你當朋友是我最快樂的時候
Huh?
咦？
That's why I talked to you even though I know you hate me.
所以就算知道你討厭我 我也要跟你講話
I'm sorry.
對不起
I misunderstood you.
我…一直以來都誤會你了
What's that? You're being so honest.
怎麼了？變得超坦率的
I…
我…
Never even considered how you actually felt.
從來沒考慮過你真正的想法
I became more and more stubborn,
變得越來越傲慢
and I was angry all the time.
時不時就在生氣
It's no wonder someone like me ends up alone.
因為這樣，所以身邊一個人都沒有了
Did you try going to his workplace?
你有去他的公司看看嗎？
What?
什麼？
If you want him back, you need to go to him first.
如果你想要他回來 不先去找他怎麼行？
But…
但是…
I said something horrible to him.
我對他說了很過分的話
Even if you were in the wrong, you can choose to mend a relationship.
就算你做錯事 還是可以選擇修復關係呀
Just like we're doing.
就像我和你一樣
It's rare for Ms. Misono to take a day off.
味園小姐真難得請特休耶
It is.
對啊
Maybe she went on a trip somewhere.
可能去哪裡旅行了吧？
Who knows.
天曉得
Ms. Kosaka.
香坂小姐
-Ms. Misono is calling you. Line Three. -Okay.
-味園小姐打給你，3號內線 -好
Speak of the devil.
說人人到
Yes.
喂
Hello.
辛苦了
Sorry, did I mention that the draft about the internship was due today?
抱歉，我有沒有提到 實習的草稿截止日是今天？
Uh, yes.
啊，有
It's being proofread at the moment.
已經完成了，正在審稿
Thanks.
謝謝你
I'm sorry for suddenly taking a day off.
我臨時休假，不好意思
Not at all.
不會
Despite telling others to quit over their personal life, here I am.
明明我還說了 如果注重私生活，就結婚辭職吧
But…
但是…
I've learned that a mistake doesn't mean it's the end.
我學到犯錯也不代表就這樣結束了
I'm sorry for being so mean to you.
之前對你說了過分的話，對不起
I know I'm bothersome,
我知道給你添麻煩了
but thank you.
還是拜託你了
Oh. Sure.
好的
Goodbye.
辛苦了
Makoto took a leave of absence and went to Shizuoka.
真他請了長假，去靜岡了
Shizuoka?
靜岡？
Yes.
對
He said he was going camping or something.
他好像說要去露營什麼的
Hey, how about we go camping soon?
我說，下次我們去露營吧？
-Camping? -Yes.
-露營？ -對
We should get out and relax in nature.
偶爾也親近大自然放鬆一下吧？
Have a look at this.
你看看這個
Makoto was inviting me to come with him to unwind in a place like this.
真邀請我和他一起 來這個地方悠閒度假
The person you are calling is not avail--
您撥的電話目前無法…
Makoto…
真…
Makoto.
真
Makoto!
真！
I'm sorry.
對不起
I want to see you.
我想見你
Makoto!
真！
Miyuki?
美由紀？
Makoto.
真
Why are you here?
你為什麼在這裡？
I wanted to apologize.
我想向你道歉
I've been awful to you all this time.
我一直對你很差勁
I'm sorry!
對不起！
I…
我…
Wanted to be alone for a bit and needed a change of scenery.
想要獨處一下，變換一下眼前的景色
I thought it might be okay to break up with you and be on my own.
也覺得和你分手，一個人過也不錯
Honestly, your words really hurt me.
老實說，你那天說的話真的很傷人
I'm so sorry.
真的很對不起
I've been putting down everyone around me.
我一直在貶低周遭的人
I've been like a monster.
就像個怪物一樣
A monster?
怪物？
I was taking your kindness for granted.
我把你的溫柔當成理所當然
I'm sorry.
真的很抱歉
If you liked me enough to chase me all the way out here,
如果這麼喜歡我，還追到這種地方
I wish you'd have told me.
要是平常也這麼說就好了
Makoto.
真
Hmm?
嗯？
I…
我…
want to spend the rest of my life with you.
今後也想和你一起生活
When you disappeared,
你不在之後
I realized you're the one I treasure the most.
我才發現你比誰都還要重要
So…
所以…
Will you please come back to me?
你願意回來嗎？
I promise
我…
I won't be a monster again.
我再也不會變成怪物了
It's okay if you do.
變成怪物也沒關係喔
Huh?
咦？
Not every day is all fun and games,
人不可能每天都很開心
so you just have to make sure you become human again after.
在那之後好好變回人類就好了
Makoto…
真…
Apparently you can go river rafting here in summer.
聽說這裡夏天的時候可以在河裡划船
Let's go together next year.
明年再一起來吧
Yeah.
好
-Apparently their pasta is really good. -Really?
-那個義大利麵真的很好吃 -是喔？
It's hard to get a reservation.
很難預約呢
I've learned that a mistake doesn't mean it's the end.
我學到犯錯也不代表就這樣結束了
I don't want it to end yet.
我還不想結束
I need to talk to him again.
我想再跟鍵谷說一次話
SHINTA FUJIMOTO YOUNGEST EVER TO COMPETE IN THE OSHO TITLE MATCH
（藤本新太二冠 王將戰最年輕的選手）
MAIKO KOSAKA INCOMING CALL
（香坂麻衣子來電）
He never called back…
那之後，他也沒再打回來
What's your type?
你喜歡的類型是什麼？
Someone who makes me smile.
在一起時能展露笑容的人
It was fun because he was there with me.
是因為有鍵谷在，所以才那麼開心
Kosaka knows nothing about me.
你根本不了解我
Once you make a mistake, you can't go back.
如果搞砸了，就再也不可能恢復了